

# **CONTACT**

Addres
Sargodha, Punjab, Pakistan

+92-346-6320718 +92-309-6713685

Web hamzait2017@gmail.com

# **EDUCATION**

2015-2017

INTERMEDIATE EDUCATION IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Superior College Sargodha

2017-2021

BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

University Of Sargodha, Sargodha

# **PRO.SKILLS**

PHP (v7.0 - v8.1)

LARAVEL FRAMEWORK (v5.6 - v9.11)

DATABASE DESIGN (MYSQL)

**REACT JS** 

**VUE JS** 

CSS/SCSS

**BOOTSTRAP CSS** 

DOOTSTIVAL CS.

**TAILWIND CSS** 

**GIT VERSION CONTROL** 

DOCKER

CPANEL/SSH/FTP/CI,CD

# Ameer Hamza

Software Engineer & Web Developer

### **PROFILE**

Solution-driven IT professional and Full stack web developer, with 5+ years of experience in creating smart, next-generation business solutions in PHP & LARAVEL for well-established organizations. Completed Bachelor's degree in Computer science and Information technology. Experienced in planning and developing websites across multiple products and organizations. Proficiency with content management systems, Software as a Service systems, and Excel to web solutions. Dedication to innovative, sophisticated designs and collaborative problem solving. Working experience in Windows and Linux environments.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2021-Present

Maahey Inc. l Islamabad, Pakistan

#### **API DEVELOPER**

While working at Maahey Inc

- I developed backend for Mobile Applications in Laravel & PHP.
- $\bullet$  I developed RESTfull APIs for Mobile apps with token based authentication.
- $\bullet$  I integrated chat systems for Mobile apps using Pusher and web sockets.
- I integrated payment systems for Mobile apps using Stripe, Cashier etc.
   I maintained an eagerness to add to my knowledge and skills.
- I effectively participated in cross-team strategizing efforts to achieve optimal goals.
- I served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee.

2019 - 2021

SUBLIME LOGICS | Emmylundsvagen 1 Lgh 1811Solna, Sweden

## **WEB DEVELOPER**

While working at Sublime Logics

- I worked on different SaaS, CMS and E-commerce projects.
- I worked on API development in PHP Laravel Framework.
- I worked on well-known APIs like Google, Facebook, and Amazon.
- I worked in accordance with company values to achieve future goals.
- I maintained an eagerness to add to my knowledge and skills.
- I effectively participated in cross-team strategizing efforts to achieve optimal goals.
- I served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee.

2017 - 2019

aimINSIGHT Solutions, Inc l Buena Park, California

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

At aimINSIGHT, we work with small and mid-sized companies throughout Southern California and have discovered that bridging the gap between your software's basic capability and your true operational requirements results in significant efficiency gains that carry significant and measurable ROI.

- I worked primarily on Excel to web CMS solutions for the company.
- I worked on converting the Excel based management systems to cloud based web systems.
- Organized and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient
- Effectively supported various company initiatives with a range of timelines.